Knight, Max; Papers ger050
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Correspondence files, 1940-1992; 2; 109 file folders
  - Correspondence with publishers, 2.128
    - Friends of the Earth (David Brower), 1967-1981 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 33)
    - G. P. Putnam's Sons (Thomas G. MacPherson), 1966-1967 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 34)
    - Grove Press (Fred Jordan), 1985 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 35)
    - Houghton Mifflin (H.A. Rey), 1972-1975 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 36)
    - Insel-Verlag, 1963 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 37)
    - International Publishing and Media Services, 1980 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 38)
    - John Muir Institute, 1969 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 39)
    - John Murray (Publishers) Ltd., 1939; 1948; 1984 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 40)
    - The Johns Hopkins University Press, 1983-1984 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 41)
    - Lancaster Miller & Schonbrich Publishers, 1979; 1983 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 42)
    - Malter-Westerfeld Publishing Company, Inc. (Edward Gans), 1967 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 43)
    - 19th Century Music (Joseph Kerman), 1981 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 44)
    - Papageno Buch- und Musikverlag, 1971 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 45)
    - Paul Zsolnay Verlag, 1975-1983 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 46)
    - Peter Lang Publishing, Inc., 1993 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 47)
    - R. Piper & Co. Verlag, 1972-1992 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 48)
    - Random House, 1966-1969 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 49)
    - Stephen S. Kalmer Company, 1992-1993 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 50)
    - Thomas Sessler Verlag GmbH, 1985 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 51)
    - Twayne Publishers, 1974 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 52)
    - Ungar (Crossroads), 1966; 1993 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 53)
    - University of California Press, 1957-1983 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 54)
    - University of Chicago Press, 1983-1987 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 55)
    - Verlag Kremayr & Schierau, 1979 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 56)
    - Wiener Verlagsanstalt, 1939 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 57)
- Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book manuscripts and translations of poetry, ca. 1938-1992; 3; 51 file folders
  This series contains typescripts of short stories translated from German into English, original English short stories, translations of poetry and drama, as well as materials used for Knight's The Original Blue Danube Cookbook. This includes his mother's original cookbook containing her original recipes upon which the book was based. Also included in this series are the written analyses of various works submitted for publication to the University of California Press between the years 1950 and 1969 when Knight was an editor for the press.
  - Short stories translated from the German into English, undated; 3.1
    - "A Dangerous Part", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 58)
    - "A Gift from Heaven", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 58)
    - Fabry, J.P. "Ball at the Embassy", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 58)
    - Fabrizius, Peter. "Barbers Don't Travel", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 58)
    - Fabrizius, Peter. "Bygone Summer", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 58)
    - "Calafati Excels Himself", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 59)
    - Fabrizius, Peter. "The Cigarette Case", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 59)
    - Fabrizius, Peter. "Counted Out", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 59)
    - Fabrizius, Peter. "The Coveted Portrait", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 59)
    - Fabrizius, Peter. "The Doctor's Crime", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 59)
    - "Express from Chicago", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 60)
    - Fabrizius, Peter. "The Find", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 60)
    - "Grotesque Dancer", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 60)
    - "The Humourist", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 60)
    - "It pays to be honest", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 60)
    - "Jinga Janga", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 60)
    - Fabrizius, Peter. "The Kind Man", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 61)
    - "Let's Be Realistic!", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 61)
    - "Life of a Hair", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 61)
    - "Lost and Found", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 61)
    - "Love on the 7:41", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 61)
    - Fabrizius, Peter. "Lucky Dog", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 61)
    - Fabrizius, Peter. "Man About Town", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 62)
    - Fabrizius, Peter. " The Martyr", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 62)
    - "New Look in Agriculture", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 62)
    - "The nile-green handbag", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 62)
    - "No Ulterior Motive", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 62)
    - "One of the Upper Three", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 62)
    - "Revolution", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 63)
    - Fabry, P. J. "Selling a Car", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 63)
    - Fabrizius, Peter. "Spring Tide", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 63)
    - Fabry, Peter Joe. "Suede Glove Test", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 63)
    - Fabrizius, Peter. "Three Previous Convictions", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 63)
    - Fabrizius, Peter. "Twenty-Four Hours of Romance", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 63)
    - Fabrizius, Peter. "What can be done with a stray glove?", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 63)
  - Manuscripts of stories written in English, 3.2
    - "A Man of Action", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 64)
    - Fabrizius, Peter. "A Trip to Totalifornia", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 64)
    - "Aunt Elpeth's Boarding House", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 64)
    - Fabry, Joseph. "The Autographs in a Gray Valise", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 64)
    - Twin, Oliver. "The Bee in Court", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 65)
    - Fabrizius, Peter. "Beethoven's Fifth", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 65)
    - Fabry, Peter Joe. "The Cat", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 65)
    - "The duBarry Diamond", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 65)
    - Fabrizius, Peter. "Exchange Husband", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 65)
    - Fabrizius, Peter. "The 50 Million Dollar Beetle-Battle", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 66)
    - Fabrizius, Peter. "Flight into the Stratosphere", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 66)
    - Fabrizius, Peter. "The Grandfather", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 66)
    - Fabry, Joseph B. "The Head of Victory", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 67)
    - Fabrizius, Peter. "Heino Pulls the Biggest Job", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 67)
    - "Instant Death", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 67)
    - Fabrizius, Peter. "Just common sense", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 68)
    - Fabrizius, Peter. "The Killer of Calville", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 68)
    - "The Last Ship (A short story)", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 68)
    - Fabry, P. J. "Man of Letters", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 69)
    - Fabry, P. J. "Mr. Horner's Holiday", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 69)
    - Fabrizius, Peter. "Murder Among the Mirrors", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 69)
    - Fabrizius, Peter. "The Mustache", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 69)
    - Fabrizius, Peter. "Peanuts", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 70)
    - Fabrizius, Peter. "Phantom Control", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 70)
    - Fabry, Joseph. "The Pilgrimage", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 70)
    - Fabrizius, Peter. "Plato Invades the Kitchen. A husband investigates what seven years of Great Books have done to the women of America", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 70)
    - "Princess Zorinda. A synopsis", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 71)
    - Fabry, Peter Joe. "The Purple Plane", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 71)
    - Fabrizius, Peter. "Rental Exchange", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 71)
    - Fabrizius, Peter. "Shrilby", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 72)
    - Fabrizius, Peter. "The Shuttle", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 72)
    - Fabry, P. J. "Sole Survivor", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 72)
    - Fabrizius, Peter. "Stitch in Time", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 72)
    - Fabrizius, Peter. "The Story of the Ugliest Woman in the World", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 73)
    - "Take it Easy", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 73)
    - Fabrizius, Peter. "The Tell-Tale Snap", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 73)
    - "The Three Tonis", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 74)
    - "Truth for an Hour", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 74)
    - Fabrizius, Peter. "When Everything Is Over", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 74)
    - Fabrizius, Peter. "The Wonderful Pew", Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 74)
  - Untitled story in German, Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 75)
  - "The Stories of Peter Fabrizius". Collection of English stories and articles, Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 76)
    Typescripts and photocopies of published stories.
  - "Sissy Gripsholm project. Ms. California Reportage". Essays in German about California, with the comment "California seen through the eyes of a European reporter", Undated; typescripts (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 77)
  - Further material for the "Reportage" project, Undated; clippings, photocopies, typescripts (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 78)
  - The Original Blue Danube Cookbook, Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 79)
    Reviews.
  - The Original Blue Danube Cookbook. Correspondence, Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 80)
  - Recipes from Laura Hoffer, Knight's maternal grandmother. Handwritten, Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 81)
  - Muschi's (Knight's mother) original recipe book, upon which The Original Blue Danube Cookbook was based, Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 82)
  - Muschi's original recipes. Handwritten and typed in spiral notebook, Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 83)
  - Viennese recipes, clippings, Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 84)
  - "My Bohemian Zoo (The Emu Verses)". Mock-up of original calendar with sketches and verses, Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 85)
  - Zany Zoo. Original illustrations for the book, Undated (Box 2 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 86)
  - Translations, of poetry and drama by Max Knight, 3.15
    - Brecht, Bertolt. "The Bread Shop" ("Der Brotladen"), Undated; typescript (Box 3 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 1)
    - Brecht, Bertolt. "Turandot or The Congress of the Laundrymen", Undated; typescript (Box 3 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 2)
    - "The Lighter Side of the Muse. Translations of German Poetry by Max Knight". Copies of original German poems and translations into English, Undated (Box 3 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 3-4)
    - "Stroll Through Time. A Personal Anthology of German Poetry Translations by Max Knight", Undated; photocopies of texts and typescripts (Box 3 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous poetry translations by Knight, Undated; typescripts, photocopied texts (Box 3 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 6)
    - Fricker, Peter Racine. "Some Superior Nonsense", Undated (Box 3 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 7)
      Photocopy of score (original score housed in oversize container); Text by Christian Morgenstern. Translated by Max Knight.
    - Jones, Robert Frederick. "The purple cow". Score, Undated (Box 3 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 8)
    - Reviews of Morgenstern translations done by Max Knight, Undated (Box 3 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 9)
  - Unpublished poetry by Knight, Undated; typescripts, carbons, photocopies (Box 3 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 10)
  - Manuscript analyses (primarily by Knight) of books submitted for publication to the University of California Press, 3.17
    - Manuscript analyses, A - C, 1950-1959 (Box 4 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 1)
    - Manuscript analyses, D - F, 1950-1959 (Box 4 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 2)
    - Manuscript analyses, G - J, 1950-1959 (Box 4 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 3)
    - Manuscript analyses, K - L, 1950-1959 (Box 4 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 4)
    - Manuscript analyses, M - P, 1950-1959 (Box 4 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 5)
    - Manuscript analyses, R - Z, 1950-1959 (Box 4 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 6)
    - Manuscript analyses, A - C, 1960-1969 (Box 4 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 7)
    - Manuscript analyses, D - G, 1960-1969 (Box 4 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 8)
    - Manuscript analyses, H - K, 1960-1969 (Box 4 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 9)
    - Manuscript analyses, L - M, 1960-1969 (Box 4 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 10)
    - Manuscript analyses, N - R, 1960-1969 (Box 4 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 11)
    - Manuscript analyses, S - Z, 1960-1969 (Box 4 (3-Manuscripts of short stories (co-authored), book m), Folder 12)
- Clippings of published stories and essays, 1930-1992; 4; 84 file folders
  This series consists primarily of newspaper clippings, which have been separated into three distinct time periods: 1) 1930-1938; 2) 1938-1945 (the war years); and 3) 1945-1993. Within each time period, the clippings are separated into German-language and English-language articles and arranged alphabetically. Whenever a piece appeared under a pseudonym or name other than the Peter Fabrizius pen name, the alternate name is included in the listing.
  Published primarily under the joint pseudonym of Peter Fabrizius (Fabricius) unless otherwise indicated, with date of first known publication.
  - Clippings in German, 1930-1938; 4.1
    - "Abenteuer eines Amateurpiloten: Menschenschmuggel über den Ozean", 1935 May 22 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 1)
    - Förster, Peter. "Aberglauben", 1937 August 15 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 1)
    - "Die Aloe", 1937 June 27 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 1)
    - "Altsalzburger Bauernball in London", 1937 December 7 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 1)
    - Kuehnel, Max Eugen. "Am Telephon", 1931 April 3 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 1)
    - "Der anonyme Brief", 1936 March 21 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 1)
    - Schütz, Myra. "Der Aufschneider", 1937 July 18 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 1)
    - "Die ausländische Zeitung", 1937 October (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 2)
    - "Banale Geschichte", ca. 1937-1938 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 2)
    - "Der Bazillus der Vergeßlichkeit", 1936 August 27 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 2)
    - "Begegnung am Hafen", Undated (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 2)
    - "Das begehrteste Frauenbild", 1936 October 28 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 2)
    - "Die Beichte", 1937 February 8 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 3)
    - Kühnel, Max Eugen. "Bekenntnis einer Meinungsänderung", 1936 November 25 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 3)
    - "Die Bernsteinkette", 1937 October 8 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 3)
    - "Der Besuch", ca. 1937-1938 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 3)
    - "Blumen für Cilly", Undated (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 3)
    - F., P. "Blumenspende", 1935 June 23 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 3)
    - "Brav, Liselott!", 1935 July 16 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 4)
    - "Die Dame und das Auto", 1936 October 19 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 4)
    - Fregoli. "Don Pedro great in die Maschen des Gesetzes", 1936 November (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 4)
    - "Drei Hüte", 1936 March 30 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 4)
    - "Duett zu dritt", 1937 March (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 4)
    - "Eduards Osterüberraschung", 1936 April 17 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 4)
    - "Ein alter Frendenführer", 1937 January 9 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 4)
    - "Ein Dieb hat Pech", 1937 April (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 5)
    - "Ein echter Rolls-Royce", 1937 October 15 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 5)
    - "Ein Edelroller geht auf Reisen", 1935 September 5 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 5)
    - "Ein illegaler Fremdenführer", 1937 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 5)
    - "Ein Märchen", 1936 July 17 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 5)
    - "Ein magnetisches Talent", 1936 July 28 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 5)
    - "Ein Mann fällt vom Himmel", 1937 May 27 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 6)
    - Peter. "Ein Weihnachtswunder", 1937 November 19 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 6)
    - "Eine Million Damenhüte", 1937 April 25 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 6)
    - "Eine schwierige Frage", 1937 January 31 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 6)
    - "Eine verrückte Familie", Undated (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 7)
    - "Eine verworfene Person", 1936 March 31 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 7)
    - "Eine vollkommene Liebe", Undated (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 7)
    - "Einmalige Begegnung", Undated (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 7)
    - "Entführung", 1936 January 7 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 7)
    - "Enthülltes Geheimnis", 1936 August 5 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 8)
    - "Die Erforschung des Menschen", Undated (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 8)
    - "Erich drückt auf den Knopf", 1936 August 10 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 8)
    - "Der Erpresser", 1936 August 26 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 8)
    - "Der erratene Weihnachtswunsch", Undated (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 8)
    - K., Dr. M. E. "Der ertrinkende Fisch und andere Seltsamkeiten in Augarten", 1937 July 15 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 8)
    - "Es gibt Streit", 1937 March 7 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 9)
    - "Fahrt in den Frühling. Originelle Wertungsfahrt des Fahrkorps des Wiener Heimatschutzes", 1934 May 16 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 9)
    - "Faschingsspiel mit der Ehe", 1938 June (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 9)
    - "Fernando Almandarez singt", 1936 May 21 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 9)
    - "Feuerlilien", 1935 September 19 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 9)